

Summary_

I am currently studying a PhD at the University of Victoria Wellington. My research is in health psychology, focusing on how mood can be influenced by physiological and environmental factors such as the gut-microbiome and experiences of discrimination. Work has led to a broad range of experience in statistical methods including structural equation modelling, multi-level modelling, and Bayesian methods. As part of my study, I have also sought to share some of my statistical knowledge as evidenced by a tutorial article on informed Bayesian analysis, and the development of statistical software to make complex techniques more accesible.

I also work with Stats NZ and Ngāi Tahu providing statistical advice and conducting analytics. My specialty is Bayesian modelling and big data. This has led to me developing skill in reproducible workflows and project management techniques which I can bring to an academic role. Example projects include heading the development of an official statistic on poverty and pipeline development for cellphone data from Spark and Vodafone.

Employment _____

University of Otago Assistant Research Fellow	2019 - Present
Statistics New Zealand Senior Data Scientist	2019 - Present
Te Runanga o Ngai Tahu Statistician	2018 - Present
Statistics New Zealand Statistical Analyst	2016 - 2019
University of Otago Senior Research Assistant	2013 - 2016
Queensland Department of Natural Resources and Mines PROJECT OFFICER	2013 - 2015
University of Otago RESEARCH ASSISTANT	2012 - 2014

Education

Victoria University of Wellington Doctor of Philosophy	Wellington Present
University of Otago Master of Science	Dunedin 2016

Awards and scholarships ____

2018	IPANZ Young Professional Of The Year (Top 3)	Institute of Public
2018	IPANZ foulig Professional of the fear (10p 3)	Administration NZ
2010 \\:\:	Vistoria Dastaral Cabalarabia (Differed)	Victoria University
2018	Victoria Doctoral Scholarship (Differed)	of Wellington
2015	Otago Research Master's Scholarship	University of Otago

Publications

- 1. Winter, T, B Riordan, A Surace, and P Jose (In Review). A tutorial on the use of informative Bayesian priors for substance research with minority groups. *Addiction*.
- 2. Riordan, B, T Winter, J Flett, and DSPJ ans T. Conner (In Review). Does the Fear of Missing Out (FoMO) moderate the relationship between social networking use and affect? A daily diary study. *Computers in Human Behavior*.
- 3. Winter, T, T Conner, and P Jose (In Review). Identifying Profiles of Affective Change: An Ecological Momentary Assessment of Flourishers. *Emotion*.
- 4. Winter, T, B Riordan, and A Surace (2019). The relationship between hazardous alcohol use and discrimination among Māori in Aotearoa New Zealand. *Addiction*.
- 5. Surace, A, B Riordan, and T Winter (2019). Do New Zealand sexual minorities engage in more hazardous drinking than non-sexual minorities? *Drug and Alcohol Review*.
- 6. Pittar, N, T Winter, L Falland-Cheung, D Tong, and J Waddell (2018). Scalp simulation A novel approach to site-specific biomechanical modeling of the skin. *Journal of the Mechanical Behavior of Biomedical Materials* **77**, 308–313.
- 7. Falland-Cheung, L, JN Waddell, MS Lazarjan, MC Jermy, T Winter, D Tong, and PA Brunton (2017). Use of agar/glycerol and agar/glycerol/water as a translucent brain simulant for ballistic testing. *Journal of the Mechanical Behavior of Biomedical Materials* **65**, 665–671.
- 8. Franz, EA, Y Fu, M Moore, T Winter, T Mayne, R Debnath, and C Stringer (2016). Fooling the brain by mirroring the hand: brain correlates of the perceptual capture of limb ownership. *Restorative neurology and neuroscience* **34**(5), 721–732.
- 9. Tong, D, T Winter, J Jin, A Bennett, and J Waddell (2015). Quantification of subconcussive impact forces to the head using a forensic model. *Journal of Clinical Neuroscience* **22**(4), 747–751.
- 10. Winter, TJ and EA Franz (2014). Implication of the anterior commissure in the allocation of attention to action. *Frontiers in Psychology* **5**.

Presentations and posters

Presentations and posters	
Using overseas surveys to produce reliable models of sexual minorities New Zealand Population Conference, Wellington	2019
Alcohol use disparities among gender and sexual minorities in New Zealand (Poster) Collaborative Perspectives on Addiction, Rhode Island	2019
Iwi data tool using integrated data and R Shiny Iwi Data Conference, Christchurch	2017
Using data to support a collective impact model of Maori potential Population Association of New Zealand Conference, Christchurch	2016
The effect of motherhood on income New Zealand Association of Economists conference, Wellington	2016
A machine learning approach to classifying life course outcomes Longitudinal and multivariate analysis network (Stats NZ), Wellington	2016
Methodology for comparing incomes between parents and non-parents STATISTICAL METHODS SEIMINAR (STATS NZ), WELLINGTON	2016
Inter-hemispheric inhibition in the autistic brain Neuroethics seminar, Dunedin	2014

Skills

- Languages such as SQL, R, Python, SAS, SPSS Syntax, Bash
- Structural equation modelling and causal analysis
- Bayesian statistics, using *brms* in R (Stan backend)
- Machine learning techniques such as random forests and neural nets
- Strong background using big data, i.e. the Integrated Data Infrastructure (IDI) at Stats NZ
- Knowledge of Tikanga Māori